# Monchai Sricharoensak

Bang Khun Thian District, Bangkok City, Thailand



nanomnemonic@gmail.com



+66909518914



linkedin.com/in/monchsricharoensak

### **Summary**

Experience in digital technology and interactive/digital initiatives from strategy development to final execution and results analysis. Managed group P&L and operations. Ability to provide strategic input, manage an account team, establish workload priorities, coordinate complex projects meet objectives, deadlines, budgets, and expectations. Self-starting advertising/marketing and communications professional with fifteen years of diverse account management experience on national consumer and B2B accounts (100kUS\$-10 Mil US\$) budgets) in multiple categories including entertainment, retails, recreation, manufacturing, pharmaceutical, wireless services, consumer packaged goods, online travel.

Solid background in media marketing advertising with a strong emphasis on digital marketing advertising and digital media and business project management: Online, IPTV OTT platform.

Consistently exceed creativity goals and customer service expectations.

Experience in handling international accounts in presenting results of consortium operations.

Strong people management skills among technical, business, and in state of arts. flexible, willing to learn, and pursue new challenges.

Perform in developing and implementing standardized policies and procedures.

Growth develops experience with a startup company turns over revenues 3 Mil US\$ within 3 years.

Strengthen the relationship with key stakeholders in both public and private sectors with such as Broad of Investment of Thailand and local government authorities

## **Experience**



#### Digital & Innovation Advisor

FWD Insurance

Mar 2021 - Present (2 years 7 months)

Manage, evaluate, deploy project Conversational AI / Virtual Assistant Humanisations AI / Integration Customer Platform / Agency Distribution / Digital Sales /

Act Innovation Champion participate as Mentor in Hackathon event.



#### GM Al and Blockchain Excellence Center

**CP ALL Plc** 

Sep 2019 - Mar 2020 (7 months)

Responsible for the strategic direction of organization functional development and training: Al / blockchain prototype that are clearly aligned to the organization's business strategies with strategic positions to ultimate outcome of company.

Identifies, assesses and improves the efficiency and effectiveness of the program and Instructional

Oversees planning and execution of all education pertaining to employee development, functional development and organization-based training programs for supply and customer chains employees and academic professionals.

Oversee the strategy and manage budgets investment and development Training System and alignment to organizational initiatives in both online and offline training

Work Closely with Chief of each Business Unit and M.D of subsidiary companies and key stakeholders to assess development needs and tools.

Lead external executive coaching bench and the process for assignment coach / trainer and team Evaluate and monitor and design effectiveness of program or curriculum

Able to manage profession trainer/ coach and hard-side trainer



#### Vice President Digital Trade and Industry Development

Digital Economy Promotion Agency, Ministry of Digital Economy & Society Jul 2012 - Jul 2019 (7 years 1 month)

Transform the international trade, logistics, and trade-financing sectors through the strategic and innovative deployment of Infocomm & Media (ICM) technologies to enhance their operational efficiency and competitiveness

Partner key stakeholders to formulate new or review existing vision, goals and strategies. Drive the ICM-enabled initiatives that will transform and create significant impact and benefits to the sectors Develop specific sector-wide programs to achieve strategic goals and desired outcomes

Work together with public and private sector stakeholders to develop a set of governance and compliance framework to provide guidelines for establishing trust in the digitally exchanged information pertaining to international trade

Engage and manage the public and private sector stakeholders to achieve the outcomes of the approved sector-wide programs

Strengthen the relationship with key stakeholders in both public and private sectors to drive alignment of Digital Economy-led sector transformation initiatives

Initiated promotion and supporting programs for national campaign digital economy industries such as digital startup initiative, digital content, digital enterprises, smart city projects

Serve to C-Suite, senior government officers and business unit leaders' strategy policy and consulting recommendations for a successful design and execution programs for digital business transformation strategy such as food, automotive, retails, entertainment, tourism

Manage budgets and implement projects supporting new S curves industries with the ministry of industry, the ministry of commerce and Broad of investment of Thailand



### Country Head/ Marketing Director / Business Development Director

24MAS Mobile Advertising Solutions AB

Jan 2011 - Jun 2012 (1 year 6 months)

Responsible for account profitability and growth. Coordinate the company's interactive expertise to create business-development initiatives and digital strategies for the client: KFC

Plan and initiate brand-building and brand engagement activities to increase customer engagement. Work and implement all marketing activities to ensure on brand positioning and awareness across all aspects of the marketing mix

Ensure and drive marketing communication in clear and powerful messages about products, brands and value proposition to each market segments

Define and coordinate marketing campaign for demand creation and lead generation with the sales team and implement lead tracking and management process

Obtain approval planning/strategy and creative briefs for promotional, educational and interactive web sites, mobile websites, and mobile app email projects and online ad units.

Work with development teams to ensure the timely delivery project

Foster strong relationships with management at operational and business levels.

Seek new business opportunities and developing relations and new customers business alliances

Engage in competitive research tracking/industry trends.

#### Country Manager / Business Director /Executive Producer

#### BuzzCity

Sep 2007 - Jan 2011 (3 years 5 months)

Strengthen the relationship with the client's agency, Toyota account, the agency's largest in billing account.

Work with the client's management system to improve better tracking of clients

Develop sales strategy and operation process for company products and services such as web site, social media services, and Web Application and Mobile Internet Marketing & Advertising strategic planning. Analyzing sales and marketing activities: Business Roadshow

Work and lead the sales team in the customer acquisition process, covering both corporate and SMI (small-medium industries) accounts.

Seek new business opportunities and developing relations and new customer business alliances ensure clients launch plan/branding effort of the wireless handset and supervised all development of collateral for mobile campaign launch: HP, Toyota, Research in Motion (Blackberry) with the digital team. Develop a web portal and mobile social network campaign for mobile phone users: Samitivej Hospital, Singapore Polytechnic, Office of Narcotics Control Board (Thailand)

Engage key leaders in annual strategic media and marketing planning/execution and promotional plan.

Present online advertising plans and creative recommendations.

Supervise and provide daily direction to account executive.

Oversee billing and all financial matters.

Manage products and services, P&L, forecasting sales, and setting budgets for sales and marketing. Collaborate with the oversea headquarters in order to obtain information for products to ensure synergies across marketing plan.

Work with the development team to ensure timely delivery. Interact and communicates effectively with management at operational and business levels.

Ensure adherence to established budgets for assigned projects; creates and maintains. Production and information schedules; create traffic reports and site usage analyses.

## Media Planning Director

#### Mindshare

Mar 2006 - May 2007 (1 year 3 months)

Develop best in class media solutions as part of broader integrated plans.

Assess, identify, and recommend media initiatives that positively influence the plan/strategy.

Effective use of data and platform analysis to develop more insightful media solutions.

Effective use of planning and research tools to develop more insightful media solutions.

Ensure your team delivers clear and coherent plans that bring the media strategy to life.

Work closely with team & Danners to ensure smooth translation from strategy to execution.

Responsible for senior level client relationships.

Maintain regular and clear client communications and build trusted relationships.

Development of new revenue streams with clients by understanding their needs.

Overall quality control for media planning output delivered to the client.

Work with the Business Director, responsible for team direction & development.

Work with the Business Director and individual team members to grow their careers through structured personal development plans.

Encourage a culture of learning, industry knowledge & personal development.

Upskill when needed to fill personal knowledge gaps to help better lead your team.

Clear delegation and clarity of tasks to Planners, strong team communication.

Oversee team to ensure accurate and detailed briefs for relevant third-parties.

Ensure team accountability of timely & amp; accurate reporting (media plans, contact reports, status reports.

Ensure team accountability of post-campaign reporting that quantifies the value of the media strategy. Ensure team accountability of loading, invoicing, and resolution of finance-related issues.

#### ✓ Marketing Director

AIS - Advanced Info Services Plc.

Jan 2004 - Feb 2006 (2 years 2 months)

Drive and implement all marketing activities to ensure brand positioning and awareness across all aspects of the marketing mix, inbound and outbound

Define and coordinate marketing campaign for demand creation and lead generation with the sales team and implement lead tracking and management process acquired, licensed management and content partners relationships and related business alliances: On-Demand Services and Value-Added Services

Promote Broadband services, Interactive TV and digital contents game contents products Assist and lead the market with modern trade and real estate trend to executive committees Manage all aspect of marketing planning, budgeting, metrics, and report

Utilize critical market &competitive research to segment and define target markets, redefine and improve the product and service position and implement the best market penetration strategy Collaborate marketing communication strategy with oversea content partners

Collaborate with engineers department and sister company for launch new services and products: (Game on demand, VOIP, Interactive TV, IPTV) of marketing concepts and monitoring of marketing activities

## Turner

#### **Manager Media Advertising Services**

Turner (Turner Broadcasting System, Inc)

Mar 1995 - Sep 2002 (7 years 7 months)

Handle all account facets of TV media planning and execution Overseen Production on-air and off-air TV program

Edited and Developed monthly media kit, maintained media relations.

Oversee works of freelance and vendors advertising agencies, post-production house

Develop creative events and materials for advertising, promotional materials, sales kits and publicity Work plan and forecast advertising next coming year ads revenue

Conduct research for producing marketing online and offline

Act as liaison between company and media and vendors; negotiable contracts; coordinate interdepartmental logistics

Manage production budgets and freelances

Produce on-air and off-air TV program; writing promotion scripts; aid mixing &editing audio and video focusing on animation

Work creative design and account service traffic

Supervise Audio dubbing and subtitling with local vendors for localization.

Assist in the development of story and art ideas as well as copy editing and proofing both video and printing

#### **Education**

## m MIT Sloan School of Management

Executive Education, MIT Sloan Blockchain Technologies: Business Innovation and Application 2019-08-07 2019 - 2019

#### Universität zu Lübeck

Msc., Digital Media 2002 - 2004

## University of Wollongong

Master, Journalism 1999 - 2000

## Chiang Mai University

B.A 1990 - 1993

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- Blockchain Technologies: Business Innovation and Application MIT Sloan School of Management 13955479
- in Diversity, Inclusion, and Belonging LinkedIn
- Developing Your Emotional Intelligence (2017) LinkedIn
- in Developing Self-Awareness LinkedIn
- in Inclusive Mindset LinkedIn
- rioritizing Your Tasks LinkedIn
- in Improving Your Listening Skills LinkedIn
- in Learning to Be Approachable LinkedIn
- in Critical Thinking LinkedIn

- in Decision-Making Strategies LinkedIn
- in Communication Foundations LinkedIn

### **Skills**

Business Strategy • Business Transformation • Creative Strategy • Marketing Strategy • Advertising • Online Marketing • Mobile Advertising • Market Research • Digital Strategy • Web Analytics